the method used in the code we've been
given for this problem
counts from zero to four that's the
integer times method
the times method counts from zero to
one less than the specified number
in this case that number is five
the block parameter on line one index
represents the number of our current
iteration
and let's look at this just by
outputting
index
you can see we're counting from zero up
to four
now the problem requires us to not only
modify the block so that it prints the
current number
which is what we've just done on line
two but to stop iterating when the
current number is equal to
2. so we want to count
0 1 2 and then stop iterating
if we place the reserved word break on
line three
our program will stop iterating after
only one iteration
so that's not what we want we need to
give this break a condition
and the problem provides that condition
for us
we want to stop iterating when the
current number
which is represented by the block
parameter index
is equal to 2.
[Music]
with that condition applied our code is
fulfilling the
problem requirements
if you were to change this condition on
line three
to break if index is equal to four
the code would actually run exactly the
same as if you
had not included that break at all
the code counts from zero to four
[Music]
when we break if index is equal to four
if we comment out that line of code and
just run the times method without
breaking out of the
iterations early you'll see that the
output is the same
and again that's because the times
method iterates from zero
up to one less than the number provided
which in this case is five
[Music]
it's important to have a good
understanding of how a method works when
you use it in your code and always check
the documentation if you're not sure